PERSONAL DETAILS

Surname	Chimala
Name	Ashton
D.O.B	07 December 1997
Marital Status	Single
Sex	Male
Place of birth	Mufakose Maternity Clinic
Nationality	Zimbabwean
Language	English and Shona
Religion	Christianity
Contact details	+263 716 344 962 / +263 778 310 176
Address	6251 Granary, Harare
Email address	jnrchimala@gmail.com
National ID Number	63 - 2028143 L 63

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A multi-talented, solution-oriented, and highly analytical IT professional with a wide range of skills in systems installation, configuration, upgrading, and maintenance. Skillful administration and troubleshooting expertise for a range of Microsoft OS, Linux and Windows products, Proficiency in grasping new functional concepts quickly and utilizing them in a productive manner.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

(Institution)

MIDLANDS STATE UNIVERSITY

DEGREE CLASS

Bsc Information Systems Degree (Hons) 2.1

(February 2017 – April 2021)

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

(Institution)

MUFAKOSE HIGH SCHOOL

Level	Passes
A-Level (2015 – 2016)	3 A- Level Passes (11 points,)
O-Level (2011 – 2014)	7 O level Passes (Including Maths and
	English)

PERSONAL ATTRIBUTES

- Hard working and honest
- Ability to communicate effectively and enjoys team works
- Ability to tolerate stress and work under pressure with minimum supervision
- Quality oriented, take pride in my work and will always strive to produce best results
- Ability to learn new things and self-motivating

Hobbies

- Playing basketball
- Reading novels
- Watching movies
- Gardening

Positions Held

Branch Secretary: Peters Apostolic Church (2015-Current)

Interact Club Vice President: Mufakose 2 High School (2016)

Christian Union Media Director: Midlands State University (2017-2018)

Christian Union Evangelism Director: Midlands State University (2018)

Stir Club Administrator: Midlands State University (2018)

Christian Union Administrator: Midlands State University (2020)

Areas of Interest

- Cyber Security
- IT Auditing
- Networking
- Cloud Computing
- Systems Analysts
- Systems Programmer
- Mobile App development

Areas of Expertise

- Computer Security
- Network troubleshooting and Configuration
- Sage Pastel (ERP)
- Computer hardware
- Software Installation
- Green IT
- Web Development (PHP, HTML, CSS)

- Databases (Windows Server, MSQL)
- ADOBE Photoshop

Working experience

CAFCA LIMITED

54 Lytton Road

Workington Industries

Harare

CAFCA is the only cable manufacturer in Zimbabwe. It was established in 1947 and is listed under the ZimbabweStock Exchange, Johannesburg and London Stock Exchanges. CAFCA is part of CBI Electric African Cables (RSA), which in turn is owned by Reunert Limited (RSA).

Position: Information Systems Intern (7 March 2019 – 28 February 2020)

Period worked: 1 year

Key Roles:

- Network troubleshooting and Configuration (Cisco Routers, Switches and Firewalls)
- Sage Pastel Evolution Administration- User support, Inventory management, ESD system monitoring.
- Rectified many issues by instituting best practices in system log analysis, software auditing and access permissions
- Daily backups for all systems
- CCTV surveillance System Monitoring and backup
- Adding new employees to the access control
- Software installations as assigned and required
- Hardware maintenance

References

Mr. A Mafenya

IS Manager

CAFCA Limited

anointed@cafca.co.zw

+263775532175

Mr. K Moyo

Assistant IS Manager

CAFCA Limited

kudakwashe@cafca.co.zw

+263777608760